ukip.org 2016-06-24

# Privacy Policy - UKIP

The UK Independence Party knows that you care how information about you is used and shared. This Privacy Policy explains what information of yours will be collected by us when you use our online services, how the information will be used, and how you can control the collection, correction and/or deletion of information. We will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information we collect by other means (including offline) or from other sources.

### Information We Collect

User-Provided Information: You provide us information about yourself, such as your name and e-mail address, if you register on http://ukip.org (including by “following,” “liking,” linking your account to http://ukip.org, etc., on a third party website or network). If you correspond with us by email, we may retain the content of your email messages, your email address and our responses. We may also retain any messages you send through http://ukip.org. You may provide us information in user content you post to http://ukip.org.

### Third Party Services

The UK Independence Party uses the NationBuilder platform to organise our community of members, supporters and prospects. You can read more about that company and its features and polices at [NationBuilder.com](http://nationbuilder.com/). When you visit http://ukip.org, NationBuilder may send one or more cookies - a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters - to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser and lets NationBuilder help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through our website. A cookie does not collect personal information about you. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive after you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the site. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser’s directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features of http://ukip.org may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled. You can read more about how the NationBuilder service interacts with and protects your information at [nationbuilder.com/privacy](http://nationbuilder.com/privacy) and [nationbuilder.com/confidentiality](http://nationbuilder.com/confidentiality).

The UK Independence Party uses Google Analytics to help understand use of http://ukip.org. This service collects the information sent by your browser as part of a web page request, including cookies and your IP address, and their use of it is governed by their Privacy Policy.

### How We Use Your Information

We use the personal information you submit to operate, maintain, and provide to you the features and functionality of http://ukip.org.

By providing http://ukip.org your email address (including by “following,” “liking,” linking your account to http://ukip.org, etc., on a third party website or network), you consent to our using the email address to send you http://ukip.org related notices, including any notices required by law, in lieu of communication by postal mail. You also agree that we may send you notifications of activity on http://ukip.org to the email address you give us, in accordance with any applicable privacy settings. We may use your email address to send you other messages, such as newsletters, changes to features of http://ukip.org, or other information. If you do not want to receive such email messages, you may opt out using the unsubscribe button at the bottom of any email.

Following termination or deactivation of your http://ukip.org account, http://ukip.org may retain your profile information and user content for a reasonable time for archival purposes. Furthermore, http://ukip.org may retain and continue to use indefinitely all information (including user content) contained in your communications to other users or posted to public or semi-public areas of http://ukip.org after termination or deactivation of your account.

http://ukip.org reserves the right, but has no obligation, to monitor the user content you post on http://ukip.org. We reserve the right to remove any such information or material for any reason or no reason, including without limitation if in our sole opinion such information or material violates, or may violate, any applicable law or to protect or defend our rights or property or those of any third party. http://ukip.org also reserves the right to remove information upon the request of any third party.

Any information you provide, including your email address, will not be passed onto any third party (other than firms working on our behalf), except where you have signed a petition or similar, where the petition will be presented to a third party.

### Queries

If you have any queries about our privacy policy you may contact us:

UKIP, Lexdrum House, King Charles Business Park, Newton Abbot, Devon TQ12 6UT

Or you can email mail@ukip.org
